
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Alejandro Sánchez Yalí - Programming, Mathematics, and Technology Blog</title>
      <link>https://asanchezyali.com/blog</link>
      <description>Welcome to my blog, where I share my notes and insights on programming, mathematics, and technology. From machine learning to software development, I cover a wide range of topics related to computer science and beyond.</description>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>asanchezyali@gmail.com (Alejandro Sánchez Yalí)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>asanchezyali@gmail.com (Alejandro Sánchez Yalí)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 05:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://asanchezyali.com/tags/number-theory/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      
  <item>
    <guid>https://asanchezyali.com/blog/en/number-theory/20230108DivisionAlgorithm</guid>
    <title>Division Algorithm</title>
    <link>https://asanchezyali.com/blog/en/number-theory/20230108DivisionAlgorithm</link>
    <description>A division algorithm is a process that divides one number (called the dividend) by another number (called the divisor) and obtains the quotient and remainder of the division. A division algorithm can be implemented in Python using a while loop and subtracting the divisor from the dividend in each iteration. Knowing how a division algorithm works and how to implement it on our own is useful for understanding better how divisions work and can be useful in situations where we cannot use predefined libraries or functions.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>asanchezyali@gmail.com (Alejandro Sánchez Yalí)</author>
    <category>mathematics</category><category>number-theory</category><category>python</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://asanchezyali.com/blog/en/modular-arithmetic/20220510ModularArithmetic</guid>
    <title>How to build a modular arithmetic library in Python</title>
    <link>https://asanchezyali.com/blog/en/modular-arithmetic/20220510ModularArithmetic</link>
    <description>In this tutorial, we are going to learn how to create a library for modular arithmetic, using operator overloading and redefining the built-in functions for NumPy.</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>asanchezyali@gmail.com (Alejandro Sánchez Yalí)</author>
    <category>python</category><category>operator-overloading</category><category>number-theory</category><category>lights out game</category>
  </item>

    </channel>
  </rss>
